Finding aid for the Getty Research Institute California Video exhibition project files and oral history recordings, 2006-2008 IA60004
Institutional Records and Archives
Getty Research Institute California Video exhibition project files and oral history recordings
2006-2008
Institutional Records and Archives
Getty Research Institute. Department of Architecture and Contemporary Art
IA60004
5 Linear Feet (7 boxes)
The records comprise the project files of the Department of Architecture and Contemporary Art (DACA) at the Getty Research Institute (GRI) for the California Video exhibition co-sponsored by the GRI and the J. Paul Getty Museum. Records include artist interviews conducted by Glenn Phillips and Carole Ann Klonarides and exhibition planning documents dating from 2006 to 2008 that include interviews, press, artist profiles, correspondence, contracts, ephemera, object lists and stills of videos featured in the exhibition.
Scope and contents
The records date from 2006 to 2008 and comprise digital video recordings, CDs, and research files of the Getty Research Institute's (GRI) Department of Architecture and Contemporary Arts (DACA) from its collaboration with the J. Paul Getty Museum for the California Video exhibition in 2008. Digital videos on three hard drives and DVDs include master and access recordings of interviews conducted in 2007 by Glenn Phillips and Carole Ann Klonarides with participating exhibition artists about the origins and development of experimental video art in California. Edited excerpts of the interviews were used in the accompanying Getty catalogue, California Video: Artists and Histories, which features essays in addition to the edited interview excerpts of the participating artists.
Records also consist of planning documents for the California Video exhibition dating from 2006 to 2008 including published interviews and profiles about artists and their work. Materials also include correspondence, artist agreements, ephemera, and object lists and images of items featured in the exhibition. Some artist files may contain DVD copies of the interviews, as well as transcripts, conducted for the project. Materials were maintained by Glenn Phillips, curator at the GRI.
Access Restrictions
The records described in accessions 2009.IA.44, 2011.IA.07, and 2014.IA.40 are available for use by qualified researchers for on-site use only or are not available at all at the request of the participants. Master recordings are restricted; use copies or digital copies exist for most of the recordings.
The following types of records are permanently closed: records containing personal information, records that compromise security or operations, legal communications, legal work product, and records related to donors. The J. Paul Getty Trust reserves the right to restrict access to any records held by the Institutional Archives.
Technical Requirements
Access copies of the interviews can be viewed online on-site and by Getty staff at: http://hdl.handle.net/10020/2009ia44
Acquisition Information
Accessions 2009.IA.44, 2011.IA.07, and 2014.IA.40 were transferred by the Getty Research Institute.
Administrative History and Project Background
The Getty Research Institute (GRI) is an operating program of the J. Paul Getty Trust, a not-for-profit educational, cultural and philanthropic organization dedicated to the visual arts. Originally established in 1983 as the Getty Center for the History of Art and the Humanities (GCHAH), the objective of the GCHAH was to foster advanced research in art, its history, diversity, and meaning in culture by engaging scholars from various disciplines in the humanities. In 1996, in order to avoid confusion with the soon-to-open Getty Center, the GCHAH was renamed the Getty Research Institute for the History of Art and the Humanities and in 2000, the program's name was shortened to the Getty Research Institute.
The GRI's mission is to further knowledge and advance understanding of the visual arts and their various histories through advanced research and scholarship, and through its activities and resources, provide a unique environment for research, critical inquiry, and scholarly exchange. The GRI's Research Library, consisting of over one million books, periodicals, study photographs, auction catalogs and special collections of rare and unique materials, as well as its online resources and databases, serve an international community of scholars and the interested public. The GRI also provides intellectual leadership through its research projects, exhibitions, and publication programs and provides service to a wide range of scholars worldwide through residencies, fellowships, hosted lectures and symposia, and its innovative digital reference tools. Through all of its programs and activities, the GRI endeavors to provide resources, expertise, and a collaborative environment for art-historical research and publication.
Through the GRI's multidisciplinary programming, first from the department of Contemporary Programs and Research (CPR) and later, its successor, the Department of Architecture and Contemporary Art (DACA), the GRI worked to advance art history scholarship of contemporary art, including sound art, audiovisual documentation of personal art, experimental music, and dance as well as a focus on the birth of video as an artistic medium around the world. In December 2005, The GRI acquired the video archive from the Long Beach Museum of Art, which increased the GRI's video art holdings to one of the world's largest. The idea for the California Video exhibition, which was co-organized and co-sponsored by CPR with the J. Paul Getty Museum, arose from the acquisition of the Long Beach Museum of Art Video Archive. The exhibition, a comprehensive history of video art in California over four decades, was open at the Getty Center from March 15 to June 8, 2008. View California Video exhibition website online
In conjunction with the the California Video exhibition, the GRI also presented the California Video Screening Series in Spring 2008. Each screening, organized by a guest curator, expressed an alternative view of the diverse history of video art in California and featured several works and included lectures or conversations presented by the hosts of the events.
Arrangement
The records are arranged in two series: Series I: Artist interviews, 2007 and Series II. Exhibition planning documents, 2006-2008.
Related Materials
The following materials are offered as possible sources of further information on the people, programs, and subjects covered by the records. The listing is not exhaustive.
California Video: Artists and Histories. Edited by Glenn Phillips. Los Angeles: Getty Research Institute and the J. Paul Getty Museum, 2008.
Getty Research Institute Public Event recordings. The Getty Research Institute. IA40002.
Modern Art in Los Angeles Recordings, 2003-2011. The Getty Research Institute. IA40018.
Getty Research Institute Pacific Standard Time: Art in L.A. recordings, 2008-2012. The Getty Research Institute. IA40011.
Getty Research Institute Pacific Standard Time: Art in L.A. 1945-1980 Administrative Project Files, 2003, 2008-2013, undated. The Getty Research Institute. IA60006. This finding aid is restricted to Getty staff only.
Pacific Standard Time: Los Angeles Art, 1945-1980. Edited by Rebecca Peabody, Andrew Perchuk, Glenn Phillips, and Rani Singh. Los Angeles: Getty Research Institute and the J. Paul Getty Museum, 2011.
Long Beach Museum of Art Video Archive, circa 1970-2000. The Getty Research Institute. Accession no. 2006.M.7.
Experimental films; Performance art -- 20th century; Art museums -- Exhibitions; Art museums -- Planning; Oral histories (document genres); Video art--California--Exhibitions; Video art -- 20th century; Correspondence; Artists -- California; Ephemera; Photographic prints; Video recordings; Getty Research Institute. Department of Architecture and Contemporary Art
- Artist interviews, 2007; Series I.; 3 Linear Feet (5 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  These records comprise interviews conducted in 2007 by Getty Research Institute (GRI) curator Glenn Phillips and Carole Ann Klonarides, media arts curator at the Long Beach Museum of Art from 1991 to 1995. The interviews were conducted in association with the California Video exhibition co-sponsored by the GRI and the J. Paul Getty Museum and feature discussions with curators and video artists about the history of California video art and their perspectives on the topic. Materials include access DVD copies as well as three external hard drives containing the master recordings of the interviews. Hard drive contents were imaged.
  Arrangement note
  Materials are organized in two sections: Access copies and Master recordings. Interviews are listed alphabetically by the surname of the artist.
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  Access copies of the interviews can be viewed online on-site and by Getty staff at: http://hdl.handle.net/10020/2009ia44
  - Access copies
    - Ackoff, Alan, March 29, 2007; (1 DVD. Running time 01:14) (Box 2011.IA.07-13)
    - Antin, Eleanor [restricted], 2007; (1 DVD. Running time 01:52) (Box 2011.IA.07-13)
    - Beck, Stephen, March 23, 2007; (1 DVD. Running time: 01:14) (Box 2011.IA.07-13)
    - Bozanich, Ante, February 9, 2007; (2 DVDs. Running time 01:14 and 00:44) (Box 2011.IA.07-13)
    - Buchanan, Nancy, February 1, 2007; (1 DVD. Running time 01:26) (Box 2011.IA.07-13)
    - Burden, Chris, May 7, 2007; (1 DVD. Running time 01:16) (Box 2011.IA.07-13)
    - Campbell, Jim, March 22, 2007; (1 DVD. Running time 01:31) (Box 2011.IA.07-13)
    - Fried, Howard, March 24, 2007; (1 DVD. Running time 02:03) (Box 2011.IA.07-13)
    - Huffman, Kathy Rae, 2007; (1 DVD. Running time 01:13) (Box 2011.IA.07-13)
    - Jenkins, Ulysses, June 8, 2007; (1 DVD. Running time 01:38) (Box 2011.IA.07-13)
    - Keading, Hilja, February 16, 2007; (1 DVD. Running time 01:21) (Box 2011.IA.07-13)
    - Kelley, Mike, 2007; (2 DVDs. Running time 1:00 and 0:19) (Box 2011.IA.07-13)
    - Kersels, Martin, May 13, 2007; (1 DVD. Running time 01:33) (Box 2011.IA.07-13)
    - Kirby, Lynn, July 16, 2007; (1 DVD. Running time 01:32) (Box 2011.IA.07-13)
    - Klonarides, Carole Ann, July 16, 2007; (1 DVD. Running time 01:38) (Box 2011.IA.07-13)
    - Labat, Tony, March 23, 2007; (1 DVD. Running time 01:12) (Box 2011.IA.07-13)
    - Lacy, Suzanne, March 9, 2007; (1DVD. Running time 01:46) (Box 2011.IA.07-13)
    - Lord, Chip and Doug Hall, March 25, 2007; (1 DVD. Running time 01:31) (Box 2011.IA.07-13)
    - McCarthy, Paul, May 8, 2007; (1 DVD. Running time 02:12) (Box 2011.IA.07-13)
    - Maughn, Cynthia, April 19, 2007; (1 DVD. Running time 01:18) (Box 2011.IA.07-14)
    - Miller, Branda, February 10, 2007; (1 DVD. Running time 01:31) (Box 2011.IA.07-14)
    - McCafferty, Jay, March 30, 2007; (1 DVD. Running time 00:49) (Box 2011.IA.07-13)
    - Mogul, Susan, April 22, 2007; (1 DVD. Running time 01:25) (Box 2011.IA.07-14)
    - Perov, Kira, June 22, 2007; (1 DVD. Running time 01:34) (Box 2011.IA.07-14)
    - Podesta, Patti, March 11, 2007; (1 DVD. Running time 01:56) (Box 2011.IA.07-14)
    - Rees, Joe, May 26, 2007; (1 DVD. Running time 01:48) (Box 2011.IA.07-14)
    - Rosler, Martha, March 11, 2007; (1 DVD. Running time 01:37) (Box 2011.IA.07-14)
    - Ross, David, January 25, 2007; (1 DVD. Running time 01:01) (Box 2011.IA.07-14)
      General note
      Please note that Part 1 was not received by the Institutional Archives. The recording consists of Part 2 only.
    - Segalove, Ilene, March 31, 2007; (1 DVD. Running time 01:01) (Box 2011.IA.07-14)
    - Sobell, Nina, February 10, 2007; (2 DVDs. Running time 01:12 and 00:45) (Box 2011.IA.07-14)
    - Steinkamp, Jennifer, March 2, 2007; (1 DVD. Running time 01:32) (Box 2011.IA.07-14)
    - Sturgeon, John, February 9, 2007; (1 DVD. Running time 01:28) (Box 2011.IA.07-14)
      Note: Audio and video cut out very briefly from time to time, but content is primarily intact.
    - Sweeney, Skip, March 25, 2007; (1 DVD. Running time 02:10) (Box 2011.IA.07-14)
    - Thater, Diana, February 26, 2007; (2 DVDs. Running time 01:04 and 01:04) (Box 2011.IA.07-14)
    - Viola, Bill, June 22, 2007; (1 DVD. Running time 01:34) (Box 2011.IA.07-14)
    - Wegman, William, February 7, 2007; (1 DVD. Running time 01:20) (Box 2011.IA.07-14)
    - Yonemoto, Bruce and Norman, January 29, 2007; (2 DVDs. Running time 01:06 and 1:18) (Box 2011.IA.07-14)
- Exhibition planning documents, 2006-2008; Series II.; 2 Linear Feet (2 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Materials are arranged in two subseries: Series II.A: Artist files, 2006-2008 and Series II.B. General materials, 2007-2008.
  These records consist of the planning documents for the California Video exhibition co-sponsored by the Getty Research Institute (GRI) and the J. Paul Getty Museum. Materials date from 2006 to 2008 and include interviews, press materials, and profiles about the artists and their work. Materials also include correspondence, contracts, ephemera and object lists and images of items featured in the exhibition. General reference materials, video transcripts, and letters of agreements with artists are also included. Some artist files may contain video copies of the oral histories conducted with the GRI. Materials were maintained by Glenn Phillips, GRI curator.
  - Artist files, 2006-2008; Series II.A; 1.5 Linear Feet (2 boxes)
    These records consist of artist files compiled for the California Video exhibition co-sponsored by the Getty Research Institute (GRI) and the J. Paul Getty Museum. Materials date from 2006 to 2008 and include interviews, press materials, biographies, resumes, and profiles about artists and their work. Materials also include correspondence, contracts, ephemera and object lists and images of items featured in the exhibition. Some artist files may contain CD and DVD copies of the video interviews the GRI conducted with participating artists.
    Artist files are arranged in alphabetical order.
    - Alan Ackoff, 2007 (Box 2014.IA.40-01)
      Includes 1 DVD.
    - Eleanor Antin, 2007 (Box 2014.IA.40-01)
    - Skip Arnold, 2007 (Box 2014.IA.40-01)
      Includes 2 DVDs.
    - David Askevold, 2008 (Box 2014.IA.40-01)
    - John Baldessari, 2007 (Box 2014.IA.40-01)
    - Stephen Beck, 2007 (Box 2014.IA.40-01)
    - Ante Bozanich, 2007 (Box 2014.IA.40-01)
      Includes 1 CD.
    - Nancy Buchanan, 2007 (Box 2014.IA.40-01)
    - Chris Burden, 2007-2008 (Box 2014.IA.40-01)
    - Brian Bress, 2008 (Box 2014.IA.40-01)
    - Jim Campbell, 2006 (Box 2014.IA.40-01)
    - Jim Campbell, 2008 (Box 2014.IA.40-01)
    - Meg Cranston, 2007 (Box 2014.IA.40-01)
    - Peter D'Agostino, 2008 (Box 2014.IA.40-01)
    - Harry Dodget and Stanya Kahn, 2006-2008 (Box 2014.IA.40-01)
    - Terry Fox, 2007 (Box 2014.IA.40-01)
    - Howard Fried, 2008 (Box 2014.IA.40-01)
    - Arthur Ginsberg, 2007-2008 (Box 2014.IA.40-01)
    - Sam Green, 2008 (Box 2014.IA.40-01)
    - Ant Farm (Chip Lord), 2008 (Box 2014.IA.40-01)
    - Dale Hoyt, 2008 (Box 2014.IA.40-01)
    - Ulysses Jenkins, 2008 (Box 2014.IA.40-01)
    - Allan Kaprow, 2008 (Box 2014.IA.40-01)
    - Hilija Keading, 2008 (Box 2014.IA.40-01)
    - Martin Kersels, 2008 (Box 2014.IA.40-01)
    - Mike Kelley, 2008; (2 folders) (Box 2014.IA.40-01)
      Includes 2 DVCAM tapes and 1 CD.
    - Kapper Kids, 2008 (Box 2014.IA.40-01)
    - Lynn Kirby, 2008 (Box 2014.IA.40-01)
    - Paul Kos, 2008 (Box 2014.IA.40-01)
      Includes 3 DVDs.
    - Joanna Kyger, 2008 (Box 2014.IA.40-01)
    - Joan Logue, 2008 (Box 2014.IA.40-01)
    - Tony Labat, 2008 (Box 2014.IA.40-01)
    - Cynthia Maughan, 2008 (Box 2014.IA.40-01)
    - Jay McCafferty, 2008 (Box 2014.IA.40-02)
    - Paul McCarthy, 2007 (Box 2014.IA.40-02)
    - Branda Miller, 2008 (Box 2014.IA.40-02)
    - Susan Mogul, 2006-2007 (Box 2014.IA.40-02)
    - Bruce Nauman, 2008 (Box 2014.IA.40-02)
    - Tony Oursler, 2007 (Box 2014.IA.40-02)
    - Patti Podesta, 2007 (Box 2014.IA.40-02)
    - Joe Rees, 2008 (Box 2014.IA.40-02)
      Includes 4 CDs.
    - Martha Rosler, 2008 (Box 2014.IA.40-02)
    - Ilene Segalove, 2007-2008 (Box 2014.IA.40-02)
    - Nina Sobell, 2008 (Box 2014.IA.40-02)
    - Jennifer Steinkamp, 2008 (Box 2014.IA.40-02)
    - John Sturgeon, 2007 (Box 2014.IA.40-02)
    - Erika Suderburg, 2008 (Box 2014.IA.40-02)
    - Skip Sweeney, 2008 (Box 2014.IA.40-02)
    - Diana Thater, 2008 (Box 2014.IA.40-02)
    - Bill Viola, 2008 (Box 2014.IA.40-02)
    - Bill Wegman, 2008 (Box 2014.IA.40-02)
    - Jonah Went, 2008 (Box 2014.IA.40-02)
    - Bruce and Norman Yonemoto (works), 2008 (Box 2014.IA.40-02)
    - Bruce and Norman Yonemoto (about), 2008 (Box 2014.IA.40-02)
  - General materials, 2007-2008; Series II.B.; 0.5 Linear Feet (1 box)
    These records consist of general exhibition planning documents for the California Video exhibition co-sponsored by the Getty Research Institute (GRI) and the J. Paul Getty Museum. Materials date from 2007 to 2008 and include correspondence, some transcripts of the GRI video interviews with artists, some letters of agreements from artists for both use of their material in the exhibition and for the video interviews, and general research on the history of video art in California.
    The records are arranged in original order.
    - Correspondence, 2008 (Box 2014.IA.40-02)
    - Screenings, 2008 (Box 2014.IA.40-02)
    - Miscellaneous local video, 2008 (Box 2014.IA.40-02)
    - "Scratching the Belly of the Beast,", 2008 (Box 2014.IA.40-02)
    - Tapes from all tribes, 2008 (Box 2014.IA.40-02)
    - Installed show images, 2008 (Box 2014.IA.40-02)
    - General California video research, 2008 (Box 2014.IA.40-02)
    - Master, 2008 (Box 2014.IA.40-02)
    - Forms, 2008 (Box 2014.IA.40-02)
    - Long Beach Museum of Art, 2008 (Box 2014.IA.40-02)
    - Audio track transcripts, 2008 (Box 2014.IA.40-02)
    - Legal [agreements], 2008 (Box 2014.IA.40-02)
    - Curators, 2007-2008 (Box 2014.IA.40-02)